Driven by a passion for innovation and a commitment to positive impact, I am a dedicated technologist with a deep-rooted interest in unraveling the complexities of data. My expertise lies in harnessing the power of machine learning, deep learning, and computer vision to build intelligent systems that drive real-world solutions. As a collaborative leader, I thrive on turning ideas into tangible outcomes and am excited to contribute to a future where technology empowers and uplifts.

## **Academic Experience**

### 2022-07 -Current

### Student

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai, India

- Worked in team environment to maintain high levels of productivity.
- Followed school and classroom policies, regulations, dress codes, and schedules.
- Participated in seminar classes with enthusiasm and respect towards fellow students.
- Collaborated on group projects to complete professional deliverables.
- Conducting research projects, gathering data and information from a variety of sources.
- Trying to learn and expand my knowledge and skills

### 2016-06 -2022-06

### Student

Maharishi Vidya Mandir Sr.sec.School, Coimbatore,India

- Followed school and classroom policies, regulations, dress codes, and schedules.
- Worked in team environment to maintain high levels of productivity.
- Participated in lecture classes and asked compelling questions to further solidify learning.
- Attended field trips with peers to study topics outside classroom.
- Supported teachers with classroom and lab preparations as requested.
- Enhanced classroom experience by utilizing multimedia presentations and interactive learning tools.
- First in Science and Computer Science Olympiad
- Runner in Science Exhibition

# RATISH R A

Student

### Contact

#### **Address**

Coimbatore, India 641006

#### **Phone**

+91 8122630290

#### E-mail

ratish.ra2022@vitstudent.ac.i

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/ratish-ra-6ab81328b

#### **WWW**

https://ratish2004.github.io /my\_portfolio

### **Skills**

Certified MS-Azure-Al-900

Python(with Numpy,pandas matplotlib/seaborn)

Machine Learning

Keras Library

Scikit-Learn Library

TensorFlow Library

Image Processing Techniques

Transfer Learning Techniques

Object Detection Methods

HTML

2010-06 -	Student
2016-06	Velammal Vidyalaya, Chennai, India
	<ul> <li>Primary and Start of Middle School</li> </ul>
2007-12 -	Student
2009-12	Bhakthavatsalam Vidyasharam, Chennai,India

My KinderGarten Years

### Education

2022-06 High School Diploma

MAHARISHI VIDYA MANDIR SR.SEC SCHOOL - Coimbatore, India

## Certifications

2024-05	Certified Al-900, MS Azure
2024-05	Certified tensorflow developer, SmartInternz(collab with google)
2024-06	Certified Google cloud with Gemini practicitioner
2023-08	Nasa SpaceApps-Gladiator Badge
2023-06	Smart India Hackathon- Finalist

# Cycling, Gaming and exploration

Cycling is my way to clear my head and discover new places. Gaming offers an escape into different worlds. I also enjoy expanding my knowledge about the world and technology. CSS

Javascript

Object-Oriented
Programming

C++ Programming
Knowledge

Google Cloud Platform

Had experience in Arduino and esp

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 20

Nationality: Indian

Marital Status: Single

Visa Status: NIL

Gender: Male

# Languages

English

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

Hindi

Advanced (C1)

Tamil

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

German

Elementary (A2)